export default {
  id: 'jp_word_ms_conjunction_1_1_1',
  name: '일어달 접속연어연체 LV1-1 (19자 / 뜻)',
  data: [
    { question: 'が', answer: ['', '그러나, 하지만'] },
    { question: 'けれども', answer: ['', '하지만, 그러나'] },
    { question: 'しかし', answer: ['', '그러나'] },
    { question: 'すると', answer: ['', '그러자'] },
    { question: 'そこで', answer: ['', '그래서'] },
    { question: 'そして', answer: ['', '그리고'] },
    { question: 'かつ', answer: ['', '그리고, 또한, 게다가'] },
    { question: 'それから', answer: ['', '그리고 나서'] },
    { question: 'それで', answer: ['', '그래서'] },
    { question: 'それでは', answer: ['', '그러면'] },
    { question: 'それとも', answer: ['', '그렇지 않으면'] },
    { question: 'それに', answer: ['', '게다가'] },
    { question: 'だから', answer: ['', '따라서, 그러니까'] },
    { question: 'では', answer: ['', '그럼'] },
    { question: 'でも', answer: ['', '하지만'] },
    { question: 'ところが', answer: ['', '그러나'] },
    { question: 'ところで', answer: ['', '그런데, 그건 그렇고'] },
    { question: 'また', answer: ['', '또, 게다가'] },
    { question: 'または', answer: ['', '또는, 혹은'] }
  ]
}
